

SUMMARY

Passionate software developer with 8 years of industry experience possessing a high degree of organizational acumen, attention to detail and proven effectiveness in communication. Recognized for contributions in hiring and mentorship, feature planning, and transforming conceptual designs into meticulously detailed project tickets.

EMPLOYMENT

SYMEND

Mar 2024 - May 2024

Senior Software Developer

Typescript, React, ReactFlow, Playwright, Jest, Storybook

Contributed to development and testing of a single page React web application with complex drag and drop UI.

SIGFIG

Sept 2022 - Jun 2023

Partner Technical Lead

Jira, Confluence, Lucidchart, microservices, GraphQL, AuthO

Operated as key technical point of contact with new partner institutions to define technical requirements based on their needs, integrate with their vendors and services, and decrease the time to market

Fielded partner requests with consideration for adoption across all clients enhancing ease of future extensibility and producing documentation with buy in from all impacted teams

Mar 2021 - Sept 2022

Senior Software Developer

Elixir, Absinthe, Phoenix, ExUnit, GraphQL, Apollo, Redis, Docker, Jenkins

Responsible for direction and development of an aggregation layer for a micro-service backend

- Successfully developed a GraphQL API which acted as the point of entry for the front-end application, heavily reducing the complexity of consumer API calls, enhancing security and increasing performance
- Maintained canonical external model by transforming downstream sources resulting in normalized data, reduction of edge cases and decoupling upstream development
- Developed robust mocking library of downstream micro-services to assist in integration testing increasing the reliability of the product

Dec 2018 - Mar 2021 **Software Developer**

Scala, Typescript, Node.js, React, Angular, Storybook, Jest, SQL, Postman, Jenkins

Key resource in developing SaaS web applications for automated investing services leveraged by large financial institutions

- Implemented micro-service modules to streamline partner integrations such as batch ingestion and legal document uploads to reduce manual intervention and improve user onboarding experience
- Developed and maintained standardized components in a multi-partner Angular front-end to support customizable flows and decrease go-to-market time of new partners

LOTTERY.COM

Mar 2016 - Sept 2018

Software Developer

Typescript, Node.js, React-Native, Redux, GraphQL, Apollo, MongoDB, Mocha, RabbitMQ, CircleCI, AWS Lambda

- Key contributor to React-Native core product for purchasing tickets and rewarding winnings
- Developed an asynchronous lottery results scraping service leveraging AWS Lambda functions to feed real time results into the main web-app, expand into more games and capture a larger market share

UNOCEROS

April 2017 - Aug 2017

Software Developer (Contractor)

Java, Typescript, Node.js, React, AWS Lambda

Implemented AWS Lambda functions to aid in analytics collection from a distributed network and created a corresponding React front-end to integrate with live analytics to drive user and investment interest

ALERT ID

Jul 2016 - Oct 2016

Software Developer (Contractor)

Typescript, Node.js, Angular, Jest

Contributed to an Angular app that aggregated and mapped public government crime data. Aided in front-end performance improvements to meet SLAs, bug fixes and test coverage to prepare for go-live date

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia

Vancouver, BC

B.Sc in Biology with Minor in Physics

Lighthouse Labs

Web Development

Certified Developer - Associate